Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have an intermediate level lesson all about a very
我是Catherine，今天我们有一个中级课程，内容是关于一种非常
special kind of person who helps you out with your kids.
特殊的人，他们能帮你照顾孩子。
That's right.
没错。
Today we want to get a nanny.
今天我们想找一个保姆。
A nanny.
一个保姆。
So, a nanny is a person, usually a woman, but it can be a man as well I guess.
所以，保姆就是一个人，通常是女性，但我想也可能是男性。
And this person takes care of your children when you're working or when you're out
这个人会在你工作或外出时照顾你的孩子。
of the house.
外出时。
That's right.
没错。
So, this is what's going on today.
所以，这就是今天的内容。
We're going to see what type of responsibilities a nanny has.
我们来看看保姆有哪些职责。
And so, let's listen to her dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
那么，让我们听听她的对话，一会儿再回来。
Hey Mel, are you up for some tennis today?
嘿，Mel，今天想打网球吗？
Sorry, I can't.
抱歉，我去不了。
I have to go to work, pick up Jake and Maddie from school, and make them an afternoon snack,
我得去上班，然后接Jake和Maddie放学，给他们做下午点心，
then take Jake to soccer practice and Maddie to dance class.
再带Jake去足球训练，Maddie去舞蹈课。
You sound exhausted.
你听起来累坏了。
Maybe you should hire a nanny to help you out.
也许你应该雇个保姆来帮忙。
She can pick the kids up and take them to their after school activities.
她可以接孩子放学，带他们去参加课外活动。
She can also help you do some household chores and run some errands.
她还可以帮你做些家务和跑腿。
Oh, I don't know.
哦，我不知道。
It's hard to find the right nanny.
很难找到合适的保姆。
You have to consider her previous work experience, the responsibilities you give her, and how
你得考虑她以前的工作经验、你给她的职责，以及她
she interacts with the kids.
和孩子们的互动情况。
I would love to have someone to help me out though.
不过，我确实希望有人能帮我。
I think you should definitely consider it.
我觉得你绝对应该考虑一下。
This way you won't have to juggle such a busy schedule and you'll still get to spend
这样你就不用忙得团团转，还能在晚上
time with the kids in the evenings.
和孩子们在一起。
I can refer you to this great nanny, Amy.
我可以给你推荐一个很棒的保姆，Amy。
She used to work for my neighbors before they moved away.
她以前在我邻居家工作，直到他们搬走。
She's very responsible, a good cook, and great with kids.
她非常负责，厨艺好，而且很会带孩子。
Oh, that's great.
哦，那太好了。
Thanks Grace.
谢谢Grace。
Can you give me her number?
你能给我她的电话号码吗？
I'll talk it over with Julie and give her a call tomorrow.
我会和Julie商量一下，明天给她打电话。
Maybe this way I won't be so tired every day and Julie and I might even get to go on a
也许这样我就不会每天那么累了，Julie和我甚至还能偶尔
date once in a while.
约个会。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some key words on Language Takeaway.
现在让我们看看“语言要点”中的一些关键词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So as you said, Marco, we don't just find a nanny, we hire a nanny.
所以，正如你所说，Marco，我们不只是找一个保姆，而是雇一个保姆。
So what does the word hire mean?
那么，“hire”这个词是什么意思？
Okay, so we have the verb to hire someone and that means to get someone to work for
好的，我们有动词“hire someone”，意思是让别人为你工作，
you and you pay them obviously money in exchange for their services.
你付给他们钱作为服务的交换。
Okay, so this is different from finding a job for someone because I could find a job
好的，这和帮别人找工作不同，因为我可以帮别人找工作，
for someone but maybe that job is at a restaurant.
但那份工作可能是在餐馆。
But when I hire someone, that means I want that person to work for me or for my company.
但当我“hire”某人时，意味着我想要那个人为我或我的公司工作。
That's right.
没错。
So in this case, obviously we are not a company, we are just a couple of people who are looking
所以在这种情况下，显然我们不是公司，我们只是几个在找
for a nanny.
保姆的人。
So we need to hire a nanny.
所以我们需要雇一个保姆。
We need to get her to work for us and obviously you would pay her a salary.
我们需要让她为我们工作，显然你会付给她薪水。
Alright so when you pay her a salary, you also have some expectations about what the
好的，当你付薪水时，你也会对保姆的职责有一些期望。
nanny will do.
会做什么。
So one of those expectations is that the nanny will take the children to their after school
其中一个期望就是保姆会带孩子去参加他们的课外
activities.
活动。
That's right.
没错。
So this is a phrase if you will or a type of thing that happens after school.
所以这是一个短语，或者说是一种放学后发生的事情。
So usually children, when they finish their classes, they have some things that they can
通常孩子们上完课后，他们可以在学校做一些事情，
do at school like for example sports.
比如运动。
That's right.
没错。
So this is very common in America but not so common in other parts of the world.
所以这在美洲很常见，但在世界其他地方不那么常见。
So just to explain, if your child is in high school or middle school, after school is over,
解释一下，如果你的孩子在高中或初中，放学后，
there's no more class, your child might want to play soccer or to go to art class.
没有课了，你的孩子可能想踢足球或去上美术课。
And these are things that you do at the school but it's usually considered an activity, not
这些是在学校做的事情，但通常被认为是活动，而不是
a class.
课程。
So we call these after school activities.
所以我们称之为课外活动。
That's right.
没错。
So these activities are usually for recreation.
所以这些活动通常是娱乐性质的。
They're not really part of the curriculum.
它们不是课程的一部分。
It's not a class.
不是课程。
No, you don't get marks or grades for these.
不，这些活动没有分数或成绩。
These are just for fun.
只是为了好玩。
A lot of people work and so they need to have these activities for their kids to stay at
很多人要工作，所以他们需要让孩子参加这些活动，以便孩子在学校
school until they finish working.
待到他们下班。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so we want the nanny to take the children or pick them up from their after school activities
好的，所以我们希望保姆带孩子或接他们从课外活动回来。
and we also need the nanny to help out with some household chores.
而且我们还需要保姆帮忙做一些家务。
Okay, so you should know where these chores are being done.
好的，所以你应该知道这些家务是在哪里做的。
The first word is household which means in the house.
第一个词是 household，意思是“家里的”。
Okay, so examples of household chores would be like cleaning the windows.
好的，所以家务的例子包括擦窗户。
Washing the dishes.
洗碗。
Or doing laundry.
或者洗衣服。
So basically any type of cleaning around the house.
所以基本上就是家里各种清洁工作。
That's right, making the house look nicer.
没错，让房子看起来更漂亮。
And so usually children have chores.
通常孩子们会有家务活。
These are things they need to do but a nanny can also help with household chores.
这些是他们需要做的事情，但保姆也可以帮忙做家务。
Okay, and also we want the nanny to help and run some errands.
好的，而且我们还希望保姆帮忙跑一些腿。
Okay, so this is funny.
好的，这挺有趣的。
This phrasal, this phrase uses the word to run but we're not running like a sport.
这个短语用了“run”这个词，但我们不是像运动那样跑步。
We're going to do some errands but the verb here is to run errands.
我们要去办些差事，但这里的动词是“run errands”。
So Marco, on Sunday I have to run some errands.
所以 Marco，星期天我得去办些差事。
I'm sorry I can't go out to the movie with you guys.
抱歉，我不能和你们一起去看电影了。
Okay, so to run errands, what does that mean?
好的，那么“run errands”是什么意思？
Well an errand is like a job or a task that you have to do but it's usually not something
嗯，差事就像是你必须做的工作或任务，但通常不是
you get paid for.
有报酬的。
To run an errand is like to go to the grocery store and pick up food or to pick up your
跑腿就像去杂货店买食物，或者去洗衣店取
clothes at the laundromat.
衣服。
You have dry cleaning.
你有干洗的衣服。
Okay so they're kind of like chores I guess but you don't really do them in the house.
好的，所以它们有点像家务，但我想你并不是在家里做。
You have to go outside and run these errands.
你得出去跑这些腿。
You have to go pay your bills for example.
比如你得去付账单。
Exactly and so when I was growing up, on the weekends my mother would always run all of
没错，我小时候，周末我妈妈总是去办她所有的
her errands because during the week she had to work.
差事，因为工作日她得上班。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So a lot of interesting words there.
所以那里有很多有趣的词。
I think we can go ahead and listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit
我想我们可以继续听一遍对话，稍后回来
with Fluency Builder.
进行流利度训练。
Hey Mel, are you up for some tennis today?
嘿 Mel，今天想打网球吗？
Sorry, I can't.
抱歉，不行。
I have to go to work, pick up Jake and Maddie from school and make them an afternoon snack
我得去上班，接 Jake 和 Maddie 放学，给他们做下午点心，
then take Jake to soccer practice and Maddie to dance class.
然后带 Jake 去足球训练，带 Maddie 去舞蹈课。
You sound exhausted.
你听起来累坏了。
Maybe you should hire a nanny to help you out.
也许你应该雇个保姆来帮你。
She can pick the kids up and take them to their after school activities.
她可以接孩子，带他们去课外活动。
She can also help you do some household chores and run some errands.
她还可以帮你做些家务和跑腿。
Oh, I don't know.
哦，我不知道。
It's hard to find the right nanny.
很难找到合适的保姆。
You have to consider her previous work experience, the responsibilities you give her and how
你得考虑她以前的工作经验、你给她的职责，以及她
she interacts with the kids.
和孩子们的互动。
I would love to have someone to help me out though.
不过我很想有人帮我。
I think you should definitely consider it.
我觉得你绝对应该考虑一下。
This way you won't have to juggle such a busy schedule and you'll still get to spend time
这样你就不用应付这么忙的日程，而且晚上还能
with the kids in the evenings.
和孩子们在一起。
I can refer you to this great nanny, Amy.
我可以推荐一个很棒的保姆给你，Amy。
She used to work for my neighbors before they moved away.
她以前在我邻居家工作，直到他们搬走。
She's very responsible, a good cook and great with kids.
她很负责，厨艺好，而且很会带孩子。
Oh, that's great.
哦，那太好了。
Thanks Grace.
谢谢 Grace。
Can you give me her number?
你能给我她的电话号码吗？
I'll talk it over with Julie and give her a call tomorrow.
我会和 Julie 商量一下，明天给她打电话。
Maybe this way I won't be so tired every day and Julie and I might even get to go on a
也许这样我就不会每天那么累了，Julie 和我甚至还能偶尔
date once in a while.
去约个会。
Alright we're back with Fluency Builder and so let's take a look at some of these phrases
好了，我们回到流利度训练，现在来看看这些短语。
now.
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
So this first phrase is a very spoken English phrase, something that you're going to hear
所以第一个短语是一个非常口语化的英语短语，你会经常听到，
all the time, especially if you're talking to your American friends.
尤其是和你的美国朋友聊天时。
We say, are you up for some tennis today?
我们说，“are you up for some tennis today?”
To be up for.
“To be up for”。
Okay, so to be up for something.
好的，所以“to be up for something”。
This is from the very first sentence when Grace says, hey Mel, are you up for some tennis
这来自第一句话，Grace 说，“嘿 Mel，今天想打网球吗？”
today?
What does it mean if I ask someone if they are up for some tennis?
如果我问某人是否“up for some tennis”，这是什么意思？
This means, would you like to play tennis today?
这意味着，“你今天想打网球吗？”
Are you interested in playing tennis today?
“你对今天打网球感兴趣吗？”
So is this a good idea for you?
所以这对你来说是个好主意吗？
Do you want to do this?
你想做这个吗？
So basically, are you willing to play tennis today?
所以基本上就是，“你今天愿意打网球吗？”
Yes.
是的。
Alright, so to be up for is to be interested in or willing to do something.
好的，所以“to be up for”意思是“对某事感兴趣或愿意做某事”。
Are you up for a movie tonight?
你今晚想看场电影吗？
Okay, or maybe you can ask your friend, are you up for grabbing a bite to eat later on?
好的，或者你可以问你的朋友，“你一会儿想出去吃点东西吗？”
Absolutely, I'm hungry.
当然，我饿了。
So to be up for is a good way to ask a question.
所以“to be up for”是提问的好方式。
After that though, we have another phrase.
之后，我们还有另一个短语。
This phrase is very important when you're trying to get someone to help you.
这个短语在你试图找人帮忙时非常重要。
So how do we ask, can you help me?
那么，我们该怎么问“你能帮我吗？”
In the dialogue we saw how Mel said that it would be a great idea to get a nanny because
在对话中，我们看到梅尔说请个保姆是个好主意，因为
she would love to have someone to help me out.
她很想有人能帮我一把。
So to help someone out, to help me out.
所以“帮某人一把”，就是“帮我一把”。
So this is interesting because you could say, I need someone to help me.
这很有意思，因为你可以说“我需要有人帮我”。
But it's more common to hear the phrase, to help me out.
但更常见的说法是“帮我一把”。
So you're not going out.
所以并不是“出去”的意思。
It doesn't have to do with space.
这和空间无关。
But we just say this phrase, to help out, means to help someone.
但我们只说这个短语“帮一把”，意思是帮助某人。
So it's basically the exact same thing, but it just sounds a lot more natural.
所以基本上是一回事，但听起来自然得多。
Exactly.
没错。
So, Marco, I'm moving tomorrow.
那么，马可，我明天要搬家。
Do you have some time to help me out?
你有时间帮我一把吗？
Okay, so you say help me out, but you could also say, do you have time to help me?
好的，你说“帮我一把”，但也可以说“你有时间帮我吗？”
And both are okay.
两种说法都可以。
Or if I'm talking about me and my friend, we're really busy tomorrow.
或者如果我说我和我的朋友，我们明天真的很忙。
Do you have any time to help us out?
你有时间帮我们一把吗？
Okay, so we just changed the person there.
好的，我们只是换了人称。
We went to the plural form.
我们用了复数形式。
Me, us, you.
我、我们、你。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And so for our last phrase, this is actually also very interesting.
那么对于最后一个短语，这其实也很有意思。
When Grace was telling Mel that she's really busy and if she gets a nanny, she wouldn't
当格蕾丝告诉梅尔她真的很忙，如果她请个保姆，她就不必
have to juggle such a busy schedule.
应付这么繁忙的日程了。
All right, so the key verb here is to juggle.
好的，这里的关键动词是“应付”。
Now I wish I could show this to you guys, but as this is an audio podcast, I can't.
我真希望能给你们演示一下，但因为是音频播客，我做不到。
What does the verb to juggle mean, Marco?
“应付”这个动词是什么意思，马可？
Well, I don't know if you've ever seen clowns or at a circus where people have three balls
嗯，我不知道你们有没有见过小丑，或者在马戏团里有人拿着三个球
and they throw them in the air with two hands and they're basically throwing stuff in the
用两只手抛向空中，他们基本上是在空中扔东西，
air, sometimes balls or pins and stuff like that.
有时是球或瓶子之类的东西。
Sometimes fire.
有时是火。
Fire.
火。
So that's to juggle, basically to have many things in your hands and be able to move them
所以那就是“抛接”，基本上就是手里有很多东西，并且能同时
at the same time.
移动它们。
All right, so when you're talking about a busy schedule, this means that you have lots
好的，所以当你说“繁忙的日程”时，这意味着你有很多
and lots of things to do.
很多事情要做。
It's important to be able to juggle your busy schedule.
能够应付繁忙的日程很重要。
That means to handle doing many things at the same time.
这意味着同时处理很多事情。
That's right.
没错。
All right, so another way to say this is because you're so busy right now, having a nanny will
好的，所以另一种说法是，因为你现在太忙了，请个保姆会
help you complete your tasks or finish what you need to do.
帮你完成任务或完成你需要做的事。
That's right.
没错。
So you can also say the CEO of the company has to juggle a very busy schedule.
所以你也可以说公司的CEO必须应付非常繁忙的日程。
All right, he has many, many things to do in general.
好的，他总体上有很多很多事情要做。
That's right.
没错。
So a lot of stuff.
所以事情很多。
I think it's time for us to listen to this dialogue one last time and we'll be back to
我想是时候再听一遍这段对话了，然后我们会回来
talk a little bit more.
再聊一会儿。
Hey Mel, are you up for some tennis today?
嘿，梅尔，今天想打网球吗？
Sorry, I can't.
抱歉，我去不了。
I have to go to work, pick up Jake and Maddie from school and make them an afternoon snack,
我得去上班，接杰克和麦迪放学，给他们做下午点心，
then take Jake to soccer practice and Maddie to dance class.
然后带杰克去足球训练，带麦迪去舞蹈课。
You sound exhausted.
你听起来累坏了。
Maybe you should hire a nanny to help you out.
也许你应该雇个保姆来帮你一把。
She can pick the kids up and take them to their after school activities.
她可以接孩子放学，带他们去课外活动。
She can also help you do some household chores and run some errands.
她还可以帮你做些家务和跑跑腿。
Oh, I don't know.
哦，我不知道。
It's hard to find the right nanny.
很难找到合适的保姆。
You have to consider her previous work experience, the responsibilities you give her and how
你得考虑她以前的工作经验、你给她的职责以及她
she interacts with the kids.
和孩子们的互动情况。
I would love to have someone to help me out though.
不过，我真的很想有人能帮我一把。
I think you should definitely consider it.
我觉得你绝对应该考虑一下。
This way you won't have to juggle such a busy schedule and you'll still get to spend time
这样你就不必应付这么繁忙的日程，而且晚上还能
with the kids in the evenings.
和孩子们在一起。
I can refer you to this great nanny, Amy.
我可以给你推荐一个很棒的保姆，艾米。
She used to work for my neighbors before they moved away.
她以前在我邻居家工作，直到他们搬走。
She's very responsible, a good cook and great with kids.
她非常负责，厨艺好，而且很会带孩子。
Oh, that's great.
哦，那太好了。
Thanks Grace.
谢谢格蕾丝。
Can you give me her number?
你能给我她的电话号码吗？
I'll talk it over with Julie and give her a call tomorrow.
我会和朱莉商量一下，明天给她打个电话。
Maybe this way I won't be so tired every day and Julie and I might even get to go on a
也许这样我就不会每天都那么累了，朱莉和我甚至还能偶尔
date once in a while.
去约个会。
So there are a lot of people all over the world who have nannies.
所以世界各地有很多人都有保姆。
I often see them when I go to New York City.
我去纽约市的时候经常看到她们。
You know, women who take out the kids and they push them in strollers and mom and dad
你知道，那些带孩子的女人，她们推着婴儿车，而爸爸妈妈
maybe go to work or have classes or something.
可能去上班或上课之类的。
That's right.
没错。
Now this is interesting because there's also another word called a babysitter, but it's
这很有意思，因为还有一个词叫“临时保姆”，但
different, right?
不一样，对吧？
There's a difference between a nanny and a babysitter.
保姆和临时照看孩子的人是有区别的。
They both take care of kids, but I think it's the time that they do it that's the difference.
他们都照顾孩子，但我觉得区别在于他们工作的时间。
That's right.
没错。
So nannies are usually hired on a contract basis.
所以保姆通常是按合同雇佣的。
You say, I need a nanny to come and watch my kids every day, Monday to Friday for the
你会说，我需要一个保姆每天来照看我的孩子，从周一到周五，持续
next six months.
接下来的六个月。
But with a babysitter, you say, hey, my husband and I, we want to go to watch a movie on Friday.
但找临时照看的人时，你会说，嘿，我和我丈夫周五想去看电影。
Can you come for two hours?
你能来两个小时吗？
Okay.
好的。
All right.
行。
So a nanny is long-term.
所以保姆是长期的。
It's someone who maybe lives with you, someone who does some work at your house, someone
她可能和你住在一起，在你家做些家务，比如
who cleans the dishes and watches the kids.
洗碗和照看孩子。
A babysitter just comes once a month or just when you need her.
临时照看的人只是每月来一次，或者在你需要的时候才来。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So that's the main difference between a nanny and a babysitter.
所以这就是保姆和临时照看的人之间的主要区别。
Now, as you said, they're very, very common nowadays because I guess it's not like before
现在，正如你所说，它们现在非常非常普遍，因为我想不像以前那样
when women usually would stay at home and take care of the children.
女性通常待在家里照顾孩子。
Now both parents usually work and so more people are getting nannies.
现在父母双方通常都工作，所以越来越多的人请保姆。
That's right.
没错。
Although nannies can be very expensive.
尽管保姆可能非常昂贵。
It depends where you live.
这取决于你住在哪里。
And so for people who can't afford a nanny, if a nanny is too expensive, the child, the
所以对于那些负担不起保姆的人来说，如果保姆太贵，孩子
baby will go to daycare.
就会去日托所。
And that's actually like a place where many babies or children are together and there's
那实际上是一个很多孩子或婴儿在一起的地方，有
one teacher or one nanny who takes care of everyone.
一位老师或一位保姆照顾所有人。
That's right.
没错。
So it's an interesting topic.
所以这是一个有趣的话题。
Maybe some of our listeners grew up with a nanny or had a nanny when they were growing
也许我们的一些听众是在保姆的陪伴下长大的，或者小时候有保姆。
up.
Or maybe you have kids of your own and you have a nanny now.
或者也许你自己有孩子，现在也有保姆。
Yeah.
是的。
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
You should check our website out.
你应该看看我们的网站。
It's our EnglishPod.com.
是 EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you guys there.
希望在那里见到你们。
OK.
好的。
Bye.
再见。
And don't forget to like our podcast.
别忘了喜欢我们的播客。